A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1979-1980
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1979-1980
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.821
This collection consists of 14,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1982 July 27.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1979-1980; permanent files, 1967-1981; administrative committee files, 1979-1980; and, ad hoc committees files, 1969-1981.
Organization
Series I: General Records, 1979-1980, Boxes 1-22
Series II: Administrative Committees, 1979-1980, Boxes 22-23
Series III: Permanent Files, 1967-1981, Boxes 23-34
Series IV: Ad Hoc Committees, 1969-1981, Boxes 34-35
Series V: Restricted Material, 1971-1976, Box 36
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous--Albemarle County; Acquisition of Birdwood Property; Allen, Woody 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous--Accreditation Notices, Fellowships, Grants, Honors 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous--Accreditation Notices, Gifts 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Adams Papers--The Letters of Henry Adams 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General--Reports, Special Requests for Admissions and Replies 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Admissions-Law 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Medical 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Affairs--Report "State of Race, 1976-1979," by Dean W.M. Harris, and Responses 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association--General--Plan for Expansion of Alumni Hall 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Women 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Anthropology 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Architecture--Recommendation to President Carter to Appoint F.D. Nichols to Commission on Fine Arts, Accreditation of Landscape Architecture Program, Discontinuance of Undergraduate Landscape Architecture Program 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Art--General 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Art--Bayly Museum--Parking Lot Project, Gifts, Loans 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Asian Studies 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Associated Western Universities 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities (3 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities--Concern for Federal Support of Research (3 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy--Portrait of Professor Frederick 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--General--Intramural Report, Reports of Team Successes (N.I.T. Victory), Personal Achievements, Physical Problems in Gym, Recruiting Black Athletes, Grades of Athletes 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--ACC 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--CFA 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--NCAA1979-1980......Athletics--Finances (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--Personnel 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Attorney General--State--Service Charge by Locality 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Auditor--Internal 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - "Ba-Bm" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Bankard Fund for Political Economy, Birdwood Property, Black Student Alliance Grievances, Black Student Alliance Annual Report 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - "Bn-Bz" Miscellaneous--Richard E. Byrd Memorial 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Biology--General 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Blue Ridge Hospital Division 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Business and Auxiliary Services 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Business and Finance--Response to Price Waterhouse Management Letter, Financial Report from 1978-1979, Sale of New Orleans Property 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - "Ca-Ck" Miscellaneous--Gifts, To President Carter Re: Re-Appointment of F.D. Nichols to Commission on Fine Arts, Exchange with China 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - "Cl-Cz" Miscellaneous--Gifts (2 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Cavalier Daily--Relations with Media Board, Student Complaints and Replies 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Civil Rights 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Classics (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Clinch Valley College--Report to the Board of Visitors 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - College of Arts and Sciences--Report to the Dean, Black Student Grievances 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - College Entrance Exam Board 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Commerce 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Community College 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Comptroller--State--Directives, Price Waterhouse Letter 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Comptroller--University 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Computing Activities--Advisory Council, Plan for Educational Computing, Procurement Procedures, Proposals for Use, Payment for Services, Administrative Computing Task Reports, Personnel Problems (3 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Consortia--General--Continuing Higher Education 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Central Virginia 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Tidewater 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Valley 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Western 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Continuing Education--Middle Management Training Needs, Prohibition of Advertising 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Council of Presidents 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - "Da-De" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Visit of Dalai Lama 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - "Df-Dz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Dishner Grant 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Darden School--General--Proposed Chairs, Coordinating Group Report 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Darden School Sponsors--Established Chairs 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Dean's Meetings 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Development--General--Contacts with Parents 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Drama--Heritage Theatre Report 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - "E" Miscellaneous--Opposition to Federal Department of Education; Egger Estate Gift; Visit of Bruce George, M.P.; Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; Exxon Grants (1 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - "E" Miscellaneous--Opposition to Federal Department of Education--Views of Congressmen (2 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - "E" Miscellaneous--Gifts, More Correspondence Re: Department of Education(3 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Economics 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Education--Southeast Asian Project, Students with Handicaps 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Energy--State 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Energy Policy Studies Center--Establishment, Statement of Objectives, Solicitations for Support, Prospectus (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Energy Policy Studies Center--Status Report (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--Visiting Professor from China, Potential Federal Support, Seminar on Engineering in Medicine (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--TV Network (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Engineering and Buildings--Use of Natural Gas, Deed of Patrick Henry College Property 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - English 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Enrollment--General 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Environmental Sciences 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Equal Opportunity Office--General 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - "F" Miscellaneous--Gifts, C.N. Ford Bequest, Visit of President Gerald Ford, Forest Lodge Land Trust (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - "F" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Faculty Forum for Scientific Research (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Faculty--General 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences--Annual Newsletter of the Dean 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Food Services 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - French 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - "G" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Grants, Instruction in Public Speaking 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - General Assembly--Resolution Re: Public Meetings at Places which Discriminate for Race, etc.; Recap of 1980-1982 Appropriations; 1980 Legislative Summary; University Position Pro and Con Specific Legislation 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - General Assembly--House Appropriations--Reports of Subcommittee on Higher Education, University Statements to the Subcommittee, Recovery of Indirect Costs 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - General Services 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Governor's Office--General--Student Representative on Board of Visitors 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Governor's Office--Administration and Finance--Policy Re: Research and Sponsored Programs, Procurement of Computers, Accrual Accounting for Hospitals, Intensive Care Unit, State Executive Institute, State Climatologist 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Governor's Office--Education--Issue Identification, Faculty Salaries, Proposed Legislative Program, Positions in Development 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Governor's Office--Human Resources 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Advisory Board of Career Opportunities, Summer Institute Program in Humanities and Social Science 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - "H" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Etc. 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare--General 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Hereford, Frank L., Jr.--General--Death of his Daughter, Marguerite 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Higher Education (Act) of 1965 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Higher Education--Title I--Grant 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Higher Education--Title III 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Higher Education--Title IV 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Higher Education--Title IX--Sanford Proposal for Compliance--Correspondence with Congressmen 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Highway Department 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - History--Honors 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Honor Committee--Poll of Students 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Housing--Off-Grounds Housing Survey, Problems/Complaints 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - "I" Miscellaneous--IBM Grant, Gifts 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Institute of Government 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Institutional Analysis--Enrollment Projections, Cost per Hour, Class of 1975 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs--Project Notification System 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - International Students 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - "J" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Jones Gift toward Golf Course 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation--Grants 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - "K" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Grants, Kellogg Fellows 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - "L" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Gift for Restoration of Rotunda 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Law School--General--Retirement of Dean Spies 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Law Center for Oceans Law and Policy 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Legal Advisor's Office--General 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Library--General--Size of Collections, Gifts, Agreement with VPI, Report and Projected Growth 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Televised Sally Hemmings Story, Honorary Degree to Dumas Malone, Meade Scholarships, Civil War Letters 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Proposed National Security Education Consortium 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development, Internal Fiscal Control Questionnaire, Internal Audit Program 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Mariners Museum--Resignation of Friends Committee, Lake Maury Master Plan (1 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Mariners Museum--Ferguson House (2 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Mariners Museum (3 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Mathematics 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center--Advisory Committee--Faculty Management and Executive Committee 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center--General--Governance, Nurses' Salaries (1 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center--General--Information Systems Requirements, Children's Rehabilitation Center Expansion, Replacement of Electron Linear Accelerator, Child Neuro-Psychiatric Center (2 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center--General--Transsexual Surgery, HMO Feasibility (3 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center Current Operation 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center Personnel (3 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--General--Indigent Care Cost, Communication with Staff, Electron Linear Accelerator 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--Monthly Statistical Reports (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--Personnel--Grievance 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--General--Visitors from Togo, Private Clinic Funds, Northern Cyprus Health Delivery System 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--Personnel 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--General--Staffing and Salaries, Analysis of Patient Care Nursing Needs (1 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--General--Nursing Salaries, Hospital Autonomy (2 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--General--National League for Nursing Accreditation, Ph.D. in Nursing (3 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--Personnel 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Mental Health and Mental Retardation 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - Music 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - "N" Miscellaneous--Gifts (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - "N" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Transsexual Surgery (Sen. Nolen) (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - NASA 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges--General (NASULGC) 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - National Science Foundation 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Newcomb Hall 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - "O" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Oglesby Chair 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - "Pl-Pz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Preston Bequest 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Parking and Transportation 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Personnel--General--Management Development Plan, Visiting Committee Report (2 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Personnel--Employee Relations 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Personnel and Training--State 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Physical Planning--Study of Buildings and Grounds Department, Space for Student Social Activities, Study of Office of Planning (2 folders) 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Physics--Annual Report of Professor Kuhlmann-Wilsdorf, Accelerator Facility, Computer Purchase 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Planning--University Projects--Lambeth Field Culvert Bridge 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Planning--Project Status Report 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Planning and Budget--Capital Outlay--Energy Conservation, Handicap Access, Intensive Care Unit 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Planning and Budget--Medical Center 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Planning and Budget--State--Reallocation of Overhead Recoveries (1 of 4) 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Planning and Budget--State--Telephone System Financing, Budget Bill Amendments (2 of 4) 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Planning and Budget--State--Requests for Reappropriations, Probud System (3 of 4) 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Planning and Budget--State (4 of 4) 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Planning and Budget--UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Promotions 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Property Records and Insurance 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Provost--New Programs--Creative Writing; Hospital Epidemiology; Return of Shannon to Teaching; Speech by Luther Hodges, Deputy U.S. Secretary of Commerce; Placement of Doctorate Recipients 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Associate Provost for Research--Ecosystems Research Center, Central Appalachian Coal Research Laboratory, Support of Research Universities, State Executive Institute 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Psychology 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Purchases and Supply 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Purchasing--Visiting Committee Report 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "R" Miscellaneous--Memoirs of Katherine Hill Hutchins, Gifts, Grants (Research Corporation), Invitations to Lt. Governor and Mrs. Robb, Stuart-Baldwin Manuscripts, Rockefeller Foundation Grant to Division of Geographic Medicine (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "R" Miscellaneous--Gifts (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Recommendations "A-Z" 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Registrar 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Religious Studies--Semester-in-India Program 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Risk Management 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - ROTC--General 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - ROTC--Army 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - ROTC--Navy 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "Sa-Sl" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Alfred Shands Chairs 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, South African Investments (1 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Policy on South Africa, Letters of Henry Adams (2 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Case Writing Center, Homosexual Students, Accreditation of School of Nursing (3 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Senate--University--Admission of Part-Time Students 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Slavic Languages and Literature 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Sociology 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Space and Energy Management--Use of Garrett Hall 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Speeches--Current--Finals, Founder's Day, Dedication of Sponsor's Hall, Fall Convocation, New Faculty Members 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Sponsored Programs 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - State Council of Higher Education, January-June, 1980--Offerings in Northern Virginia, Funds for Excellence (SCHE) (1 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - State Council of Higher Education--Funds for Excellence, Computer Services (SCHE)(2 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - State Council of Higher Education--Proposed New Programs, Eminent Scholars Program (SCHE) (3 of 3) 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - State Council of Higher Education--General, July-December 1979--Support for Research, Plan for Educational Computing, Off-Campus Courses, Discontinued or Combined Programs, Productivity Study (SCHE) (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - State Council of Higher Education--General, July-December 1979--Initiation of LL.M. Degree, Budget Recommendations (SCHE) (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Council of Higher Education--Marine Science--Admission of Hampton Institute, Consortium By-Laws and Compact, Search for Consortium Director, Sea Grant College Status (SCHE) 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Council of Higher Education--Virginia Plan--Mission Explication--UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA Mission Statement, Draft Issue Papers (SCHE) (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Council of Higher Education--Virginia Plan--Mission Explication--Draft #4, Narratives of all Missions (SCHE) (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Council of Higher Education--Notes (SCHE) 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Department of Education 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Farm--Renovation of Carruthers Hall 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - State Fire Marshal--Student Recreation Building, Primary Care Center, Birdwood Pavilion, Corner Building, Cobb Hall, McKim Hall, Executive Program Center 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - Student Affairs--General--Mid-Term Break, Dormitory Visitation, Damage to Boathouse at Sweetbriar, Marijuana Use (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - Student Affairs--General--Sorority Racial Discrimination, Report of Student Characteristics, Echols Scholars (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Student Council--General--Food Services, Housing, University Investments, Minutes of Administrative Committees, Irregularities in Student Elections, Race Relations. 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Summer Session--Enrollment Statistics, Cost Analysis 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - "T" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Murder of Parents (Press Report) 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Task Force of the University Neighborhood Study 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute--Economic Impact of the University 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Travel Invoices 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Treasurer 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - "U" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Affirmative Action Program, Ecosystems Research Center, Upward Bound Misappropriation of Funds 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - United States Savings Bonds 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - United Way 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - Universities Research Association 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - University Police 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - University Press of Virginia 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - University Relations--Meetings of the Board of Visitors, University Seal 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - University Union 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - "V" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Retirement Study Commission, Transcripts of Transfer Students 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Admissions Policy, Retirement of William S. Weedon, Foundation Gifts for East Asian Studies 1979-1980 (Box 21)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Federal Financial Management System for Research 1979-1980 (Box 22)
- Series II: Administrative Committees
  - General 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Admissions 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Afro-American Affairs Advisory 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Arboretum 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Architectural Advisory 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Athletic Advisory Council 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Bayly Museum (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Calendar 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Career Planning and Placement (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Catalogue 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Cemetery--Sprinkling of Remains 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Chapel 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Chemical and Biological Hazards Safety 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Chemical and Biological Hazards Safety--Subcommittee--DNA 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Commencement and Convocations 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Subcommittee--Processions 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Subcommittee--Public Occasions 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Community Colleges 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Computers 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Danforth Foundation 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Development Steering 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Education and Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Energy Conservation 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - External Prizes and Awards 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Fraternities and Sororities--Judicial System, Discrimination/Recognition Problems--Alpha Phi 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Fulbright Grants 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Graduate Opportunities (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Graphics 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Gwathmey Award 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Housing 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - International Students 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Lectures--Page, Barbour, and Richard 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Lectures--Special 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Library 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Master Plan--Medical Center 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Minority Student Affairs Advisory Council (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Names 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Patents (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Radiation Safety--Tritium Incident (1 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Radiation Safety--Revised Guide, Incineration Program (2 of 2) 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Registration 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Rhodes Scholarship 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - ROTC 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Scheduling 1979-1980 (Box 23)